

# Saheen Palayi

Hardware Designer

I'm a Hardware designer located in Kerala, who do design and fabricate Products and Hardware for both Industrial and commercial Applications. Mainly focused on Rapid prototyping ,3D printing, Embedded engineering and etc.. I have been pursuing new skills and technologies to stay up to date for creating better solutions. I do have experience and knowledge in both electronics and electrical over 8+ years

**SKILLS** 

- emspsaheen@gmail.com
- Manjeri, Kerala, India
- linkedin.com/in/saheenpalayi
- github.com/saheenpalayi

- +918089918285
- saheenpalayi.github.io
- twitter.com/emspsaheen

**Embedded Programing** 

Wood Working & Fabrication

PCB Designing & Fabricating

instagram.com/saheen\_palayi

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Mentor

Foxlab Makerspace

2017 - Present Kerala,India

# 3D Designer

VectorBag.com

2019 - Present Kerala.India

# **Technological Assistant**

Mesmerito

2018 - 2019 India

#### Electrician

Freelance

2015 - Present Kerala india

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

Laser Cutting and CNC Machining

PCB Milling Machine

**Welding Technology** 

IOT Based Parking system (2020)

IOT Based Plant Monitoring (2020)

DIY 3D Printer (2019)

DIY Drone (2016)

**HOBBIES** 

**DIY Projects** 

E - Learning

Programing

RC Aeroplane (2015)

Converting Bicycle into a Motorbike (2013)

# **EDUCATION**

## **Diploma in Digital Fabrication** Super FABLAB Kerala

01/2021 - Present Kerala.India

Courses

- Digital Fabrication

# **Diploma in Electronics Engineering**

Govt.polytechnic College Perinthalmanna

2015 - 2018 Courses

Kerala,India

- Electronics Engineering

# **Higher Secondary**

H.M.Y.H.S.S Manjeri

- Computer Science

# **LANGUAGES**

Malayalam

English

3D Printing & Designing

Open source Hardware

Product designing

C/C++ Programing

Prototyping

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency

**Technical Basic Education** Govt. Technical High School Manjeri

2010 - 2013

Courses

- Welding technology & General Engineering

Kerala.India

## Robotics IOT **Product Designing** Open source hardware **Industrial Automation**

Interest

2013 - 2015 Courses

Kerala India

**INTERESTS**